Rowan Torbitzky-Lane

rowan.a.tl@protonmail.com • www.brokenglass.dev • github.com/RowanTL

Summary

To work at Parathon as a Software Engineer - PDB. Logically-driven Computer Scientist with a bachelor's degree and 1+ year(s) of personal networking and professional programming experience. I admire Parathon's 45% reduction in A/R days and would be happy to provide my SQL and Python knowledge.

Education

Missouri University of Science and Technology

B.S. Computer Science, with a Minor in Mathematics.

Summa Cum Laude

Rolla, MO December 2024

Experience

NSF REU Program

Missouri University of Science and Technology

May 2024 - October 2024

Rolla, MO

- Present Research Findings Weekly at Meetings
- Experiment with LLMs and Next-Token Prediction on Genome Sequences
- Clean text data with Scikit-learn and Scikit-bio

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Center for Intelligent Infrastructure

May 2023 - October 2023

Rolla, MO

- Calculate Optical Flow with MATLAB and C++ utilizing Slurm
- Use Django to manage Web Requests
- Program User Interfaces with TypeScript
- Manipulate videos using OpenCV and Python
- Perform Annotations for Image Segmentation Neural Networks
- Participated in Weekly Meetings discussing State of Project

Data Science Co-Op

Hunter Engineering Company

January 2022 - August 2022

Bridgeton, MO

- Train Convolutional Neural Networks with YOLO and PyTorch
- Utilize Microsoft Excel for Data Annotation
- Design and write APIs with FastAPI and Flask
- Containerize said APIs with Docker
- Program internal tooling leveraging Pandas and Microsoft SQL
- Implement workflows into internal Azure DevOps Git repository
- Attend Bi-Weekly Lunch and Learns covering Full-Time Employee Responsibility

Personal Projects

Self-Hosted Linux Server

January 2023 - Present

- Host PostgreSQL Server for University Projects
- Interact with Router Firewall
- Host Wireguard Virtual Private Network
- Manage Reverse Proxy connections with Nginx
- Point Domain Names via A Records
- Self Host a Git Server